<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Path Nirvana Foundation</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Path Nirvana Foundation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.132.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 11:23:21 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Educational Software</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 11:23:21 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/software/</guid>
      <description>As an organization at the forefront of Buddhist and spiritual education in Sri Lanka, we have developed numerous free-to-use websites and mobile apps for the benefit of the global Buddhist community.
Our Websites tipitaka.app - contains the Chaṭṭha Saṃgāyanā Tipiṭaka and allows searching and dictionary function for many different languages. tipitaka.lk - Contains the Buddha Jayanthi Tipitaka, the attakatha and the Sinhala Translations. In addition there is a library of over 1000 Buddhist books hosted in our online library.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 21:56:31 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Path Nirvana Foundation (PNF) is a US non profit organization. It was formed in September 2015 with the goal of providing support for a variety of charitable causes to advance the humanity towards a better future. Uplifting physical, mental and spiritual well being of the humanity is one of the main focus areas for PNF.
We invite everyone to take a look at our projects and provide us support in any method possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 17:17:31 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/donate/</guid>
      <description>Since Path Nirvana Foundation (PNF) is a US non profit organization, your donation would be exempt from taxes to the limits allowed by federal tax laws. PNF is run by volunteers and therefore no administrative costs are involved in PNF. Even the wire transfer fees will be born by our volunteers, so that 100% of your donation will reach the cause/project you are supporting.
You can initiate a Zelle transfer to our email info@pathnirvana.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promote Home Gardens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/home-garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 16:54:23 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/home-garden/</guid>
      <description>To face the current food crisis in Sri Lanka we have started a Home garden project. As the initial kick start we have donated plants, seeds and compost to 1,000 families. These were donated to 28 urban areas in Dehiwala and Ratmalana.
Continuous monitoring and support for these families will be done through 5 officials per urban area (Grama Seva Officer, Economic Dev Officer, Agriculture Officer and two Trainees). Officials will visit each home garden and provide guidance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID crisis in Sri Lankan Hospitals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 11:37:42 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid/</guid>
      <description>Path Nirvana Foundation (USA) and Kalana Mithuro Organization (France) have worked together with Sri Lankan doctors and hospitals to compile a list of essential medical equipment. These items would be used to help vulnerable COVID victims like pregnant mothers. The two foundations have formed a way to purchase and ship this equipment to Sri Lanka. The cost of these items are really high. So we urge all supporters to help us in this cause.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Providing 3 months of Amisha Dana for 37 monastics at the Anthar Sumbuddha Pirivena-Kalpitiya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/kalpitiya-pirivena/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 12:01:32 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/kalpitiya-pirivena/</guid>
      <description>Project for Providing three months of Amisha Dana for 37 monastics at the Anthar Sumbuddha Pirivena-Kalpitiya during Covid-19.
As a result of the lockdown and curfew imposed by the government of Sri Lanka, many of the families in this non-Buddhist community in Kalpitiya area are facing many difficulties in providing basic needs to the families. All of the monastic temples also in this area are facing much difficulties receiving basic dana meals now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help Poor Families cope with the Virus outbreak</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-poor-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 12:05:38 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/covid-poor-families/</guid>
      <description>As a result of the lockdown and curfew imposed by various local governments in South Asia many of the families who had non-regular jobs are out of work unable to buy food and medicine. We are coordinating with various local Sri Lankan organizations in the ground to provide necessary groceries directly to the most needed neighborhoods. Some photos from one of the projects that was recently completed are posted below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buy building material for Sandagiri Seya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sandagiri-seya/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 12:14:50 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sandagiri-seya/</guid>
      <description>We are helping to build the Sandagiri Stupa in Hanthana Kandy. You can help to buy either Cement or Gadol as indicated below.
1000 Gadol or 25 Cement bags for just 138 USD. Donate Here </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help donate Tipitaka Tablets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tipitaka-tablets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 12:17:42 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tipitaka-tablets/</guid>
      <description>The offering of 5000 Tipitakas at one given time could well be considered the largest ever Dharma Dana made to monks in the recent past. The concept itself arises from the disheartening situation found currently worldwide where the pristine Buddha word which is given the supreme place of teacher and guide in the absence of Lord Buddha himself, is being distorted and interpreted as thought fit by certain monks creating doubt and confusion among the followers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Land extension to facilitate Pariyatthi Project in Katana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/katana-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 12:19:13 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/katana-land/</guid>
      <description>We have decided to support the following project to buy a land for building a Pariyatti center. You can donate to buy at least one perch (50,000 LKR or just 275 USD). Following is the letter explaining the project.
Dear Path Nirvana Foundation
Regarding proposed land extension for facilitate Pariyatthi Project in Katana.
Katana Sri Gangārāma Vipassanā Meditation center located here is an affiliated monastery to the Sri Kalyānī Yogasrama Samstha.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hospital Service Support Foundation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hospital-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 12:37:19 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hospital-services/</guid>
      <description>Hospital Service Support Foundation is established with the aim of providing the Opportunity to aid the growing health-care needs of Sri Lanka. Our primary aim is to create a sustainable platform to connect both the US living Sri Lankan community and other local organizations interested in supporting the welfare needs of developing countries. The partnership with Hospital Services Council (HSC), an existing non-profit organization in Sri Lanka, paves the necessary path to distribute services collected here in the US and successfully distribute them to the needed patients in local hospitals in Sri Lanka.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donating 100 Tipitaka Book sets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/tipitaka-book-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 12:38:16 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/tipitaka-book-sets/</guid>
      <description>Monks in Labunoruwa monastery are donating 100 tipitaka book sets to needy temples, monasteries and other dharma education institutes across Sri Lanka in an attempt to squash the adharma distribution by rejuvenating the tipitaka learning in Sri Lanka.
The donation will happen in front of Ruwanweli Maha Seya in Anuradhapura on May 12th where a ceremony will be held whole day information about it can be found here. May 12th is also the 50th birthday of Ven Mankadawala Sudassana, chief meditation master of Labunoruwa monastery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alawwe Anomadassi Thero’s Building</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/alawwe-building/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 12:41:59 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/alawwe-building/</guid>
      <description>Alawwe Anomadassi Thero’s Building in Anuradhapura. Cost around 10 Million. 2 Million already donated.
Here are the the estimates and the design of the building. Construction was started on 1/1/2018 – below is a photo from that day. Thero sent us an account number to deposit the funds. M.P.T. Wijewickrama, BOC, Matale, 76273401</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helping Flood Victims – 2017 May</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/flood-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 12:45:14 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/flood-2017/</guid>
      <description>Be a part of the flood donation programme, conducted by Path Nirvana Foundation.
Now you can donate to the people who are affected by the floods and landslides in different parts of the country with long term support items such as clothes, water filters, mattresses and medicine.
Path Nirvana Foundation is collecting funds to distribute goods among various projects helping the relief operations in Sri Lanka. Please make your charitable donation using our donation instructions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Help Buy an Ambulance for Bhikku Hospital</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bhikku-ambulance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 12:55:59 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bhikku-ambulance/</guid>
      <description>There is an opportunity to help the Bhikkhu hospital started by the Galigamuwe Gnanadeepa thero in Horana.
Link to the Facebook Video about this project
As of a week ago 2.5 million was collected from donors around the world out of about 10 million estimated amount needed to buy the Ambulance. More information about this Bhikkhu hospital can be obtained from the two websites below.
http://healthcaremonastery.com/ http://seelasuwaarana.com/ To receive updates about our charity projects please subscribe to our website pathnirvana.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PET CT Scanner for Cancer Hospital</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pet-cancer-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 12:52:32 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pet-cancer-2016/</guid>
      <description>Maharagama Cancer Hospital in Sri Lanka is badly in need of a PET CT scanner. So far only one private hospital has the facilities necessary to do PET scans. One scan costs around Rs.150,000 and during the course of treatment most patients need to undergo many scans but they cannot afford private scans.
A PET CT scanner costs approximately Rs. 200 million. The lack of a PET CT scanner has caused complications and irregularities in the diagnosis of cancer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Helping Basawakkulama Monastery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/basawakkulama-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 12:50:16 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/basawakkulama-2016/</guid>
      <description>Ven Mankadawala Sudassana thero is one of the most prominent meditation teachers in Sri Lanka. A 3 story meditation center and a bhikku training center is being built in Anuradhapura, Sri Lanka for the furtherance of his dhamma teaching activities. The center will be used by local and international Sangha community to research and practice the dhamma in accordance with the Pali Canon.
There is a rare opportunity for you to help in the construction of Center.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
